J. Gus Liebenow Collection, 1882-2011 LCP2007/02
Liberian Collections
J. Gus Liebenow Collection
1882-2011
Liberian Collections
LCP2007/02
18 cubic feet 18 records cartons
J. Gus Liebenow was a professor emeritus of political science at Indiana University. Starting his tenure in 1958, Liebenow also served as the dean for Research and Advanced Studies as well as vice president and dean of Academic Affairs. In 1961, he also found the University's African Studies Program. This collections consists of lecture notes, personal files, department records, Liebenow's writings, and materials from numerous organizations he was affiliated with.
Access Restrictions
Closed for research. One box of personal records is restricted.
Biographical Note
J. Gus Liebenow joined the faculty of Indiana University in 1958 and founded the university's African Studies Program in 1961, which he directed for 11 years. He also served as dean for research and advanced studies as well as vice president and dean for academic affairs on the Bloomington campus.
In 1987, he was named Rudy Professor by the university trustees, who award the title for excellence. He retired in 1990. An expert on Liberia, Professor Liebenow testified on developments in the republic before several Congressional committees in the 1970s and 1980s. On retirement, he received the first Lifetime Achievement Award of the Liberian Studies Association, a group of scholars from around the world.
He was a prolific writer on African politics, education, history, agriculture and urbanization. Among his numerous books are "Liberia: The Evolution of Privilege" (Cornell University Press, 1969 ), "Liberia: The Quest for Democracy" (Indiana University Press, 1987 ) and "African Politics: Crises and Challenges" (Indiana University Press, 1986 ). Professor Liebenow was born in Berwyn, Ill. He graduated from the University of Illinois, where he received a master's degree in 1950. After being a Goodwin Fellow at Harvard University in 1951-1952, he earned a Ph.D. in political science at Northwestern University in 1955.
Series Arrangment
The J. Gus Liebenow Collection is divided into 6 series: Indiana University, Outside Organizations, Personal Files, Subject Files, Writings, and Restricted Materials
Scope and Content
The J. Gus Liebenow Collection consists of 15 linear feet of documents spanning the years from 1949-1999. As much as possible the organization and folder titles reflect Liebenow's personal naming convention. This collection is divided into 6 series:
Indiana University
Outside Organizations
Personal Files
Subject Files
Writings
Restricted Files
The Indiana University series consists of papers for both the Political Science and African Studies departments, including committees, programs, course syllabi, interdepartmental correspondence, and meeting minutes. Also included in this series are Liebenow's lecture notes for various classes he taught, and materials from other university organizations.
The Outside Organizations series consists of materials from numerous organizations and conferences Liebenow was affiliated with. These include the African Studies Association, Friends of Liberia, Liberian Studies Association, Universities Field Staff International, and the South African Development Coordination Conference, as well as materials from other universities.
The Personal Files series contains records on former students, colleagues, friends, and co-workers. These include correspondence, newspaper clippings, dissertation drafts, and manuscripts.
The Subject Files series contains photographs, ephemera and memorabilia, and other materials that don't easily fall into another series.
The Writings series contains conference papers submitted by Liebenow, as well as his drafts and copies of his published materials. Correspondence with various publishing houses are also found in this series.
The Restricted Files series conatins personal files that are not open for research.
Separated Materials
Audio and video materials have been separated from the collection and stored elsewhere. Most of these items are cassettes of Liebenow's lectures and Liberian music. All of the video reels are in German.
Copyright Transferred
Copyright interests for this collection have been transferred to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, contact the Indiana University Liberian Collections
Liberia; Liebenow, J. Gus, 1925-; Carter, Gwendolen Margaret, 1906-1991; Carter, Jeanette E.; D'Azevedo, Warren L.; African Studies Association; Friends of Liberia (Organization); Indiana University; Indiana University. African Studies Program; Indiana University. Department of Political Science; Liberian Studies Association; Universities Field Staff International
- Indiana University (Box 1)
  - African Studies
    - African Exchange Committee, undated, 1984-1990 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Association in Germany, 1988 (Box 1)
    - African Universities, undated, 1959-1976 (Box 1)
    - American – Soviet Symposium on Contemporary Africa, undated, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
    - Appeals on Minors, undated, 1976-1983 (Box 1)
    - Botswana,, undated, 1970-1977 (Box 1)
    - Colloquium on Drought and Hunger in Africa: "Denying Famine a Future",, undated, 1985- 1986 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1984 (Box 1)
    - Death of L.E. Clark, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1984-1988 (Box 1)
    - GLCA Africanists,, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Graduated Minors Contact List, undated (Box 1)
    - Hans Wolff Lectureship Committee,, undated, 1981-1988 (Box 1)
    - "Identity in Africa Conference,, undated, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Institute of World Affairs, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Interdependence: The African Connection, undated, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Language Studies, undated (Box 1)
    - Lesotho Maps, undated (Box 1)
    - Library Committee, undated, 1978-1987 (Box 1)
    - Malawi,, undated, 1971-1983 (Box 1)
    - Malawi Exchange, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
    - Members of the Program of African Studies, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Minor Statements, undated, 1974-1988 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1969-1991 (Box 1)
    - Outreach, undated, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - "Pluralism and Democracy in Africa" Conference,, undated, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Program News and Events, 1966-2011 (Box 1)
    - Program of African Studies, undated, 1950-1971 (Box 1)
    - Program of the "History and Culture Seminar", undated, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Progress Report, 1960-1970 (Box 1)
    - Receipts, undated, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Regional & County Development Study, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Schedule of Classes, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - South African Committee for Higher Education, 1984, undated (Box 1)
    - Soviet – American Conference on Sub-Saharan Africa,, undated, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Soviet – American Conference on Sub-Saharan Africa - photographs, 1984 (Box 1)
    - U.S. – China African Studies Exchange Committee,, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Zimbabwe, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Bloomington Faculty Council (Box 2)
    - Academic Handbook, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - Administrative Salary Levels, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Agenda Committee, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
    - Appointing Students to University Committees, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Athletics Committee, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Budgetary Affairs, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - Constitution, By-Laws, and Other Campus Documents, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
    - Dean of Faculties – Search and Screen Committee, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Film Policy, 1976 (Box 2)
    - IDS Publications Board, 1969-1977 (Box 2)
    - Institute for Advanced Study, 1977 (Box 2)
    - J. Gus Liebenow Statement, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - Latino Affairs, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Liaison with Bloomington Administrative Committees, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
    - Merged Schools Tenure/Promotion, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, Agendas, and Related Documents, 1971-1976; January-September 1977; October-December 1977; 1978; 1979-1988 (Box 2)
      General
      1971-1976
      January-September 1977
      October-December 1977
      1978
      1979-1988
    - Nominations Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Parking, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Part-Time Faculty, Lecturers, and Professional Librarians, 1977 (Box 2)
    - "Student Life" Study, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Teaching Evaluation – Peer, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Tenure Procedure, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Trustees Faculty Relations Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - University-City Relations, 1976 (Box 2)
    - University Governance, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Lecture Notes (Box 3)
    - Administrative Structure of Interior Service, undated (Box 3)
    - The African Press – Journalists, Media, etc., undated (Box 3)
    - Americo-Liberian Ethic, undated (Box 3)
    - Anatomy of Indirect Rule, undated (Box 3)
    - Application to Rest of U.S., undated (Box 3)
    - Biographical Information on District Commissioners, undated (Box 3)
    - British Pre-Industrial Revolution, undated (Box 3)
    - The Bureaucracy, undated (Box 3)
    - Case for Colonialism, undated (Box 3)
    - Chaga, undated (Box 3)
    - Code of Laws/Aboriginal Law undated, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Communicationundated, 1960-1962 (Box 3)
    - Conflicting State Claims, undated (Box 3)
    - The Congoes, undated (Box 3)
    - Constitutionalism – Independence of Legislature and Judiciary, undated (Box 3)
    - Cooperative Society, undated (Box 3)
    - Country Systems, undated, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Crisis, Inviting Interventionundated, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Dams in Africa, undated (Box 3)
    - District Council, undated (Box 3)
    - Economic Planningundated, 1961 (Box 3)
    - Educationundated, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
    - Equality of New States, undated (Box 3)
    - Evidence of Change, undated (Box 3)
    - Evidence of Dependency, undated (Box 3)
    - Extension of Council, undated (Box 3)
    - Foreign Contacts and Affairs, undated, 1959-1961 (Box 3)
    - General Overview of Liberia, undated (Box 3)
    - Government Financesundated, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
    - The Horn of Africa,, undated, 1981-1986 (Box 3)
    - Judiciary, undated (Box 3)
    - Knowledge and Political Controlundated, 1961 (Box 3)
    - Land and Geography Factorsundated, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Land Companies, undated (Box 3)
    - Legal Standing of Ordinance, undated (Box 3)
    - Liberian Economy/Finances, undated, 1955-1961 (Box 3)
    - Liberian Elite-Criteria of Leadership Groupings undated, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
    - Liberian Frontier Force, undated, 1961-1970 (Box 3)
    - Lindi, undated (Box 3)
    - Liwali, undated (Box 3)
    - Local/Central Relationship, undated (Box 3)
    - Local Government, undated (Box 3)
    - Makonde, undated, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Makua and Masasi, undated (Box 3)
    - Micropolitics in Tanzania, undated, 1956-1964 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Lecture Notesundated, 1948-1980 (Box 3)
    - Multiple Rules of District Commissioners, undated (Box 3)
    - Nationalism, undated (Box 3)
    - Native Administration, undated (Box 4)
    - Parameters of Traditional Politics, undated (Box 4)
    - Party Systems – True Whigs, undated, 1959-1961 (Box 4)
    - Pawning/Slavery, undated (Box 4)
    - Performance of Chiefs, undated (Box 4)
    - Poro-Indirect Rule, undated (Box 4)
    - Post- 1956, undated (Box 4)
    - Poverty, undated (Box 4)
    - The Presidencyundated, 1959-1960 (Box 4)
    - Pressure Groups-Communal Activities undated, 1960-1968 (Box 4)
    - Public Education, undated (Box 4)
    - Quebec Act, etc., undated (Box 4)
    - Recruitment of Chiefs, undated (Box 4)
    - Regional Organizational Study, undated (Box 4)
    - Religion undated, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Rewards of the Eliteundated, 1958-1961 (Box 4)
    - Rewards to Chiefs undated, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Role of the Military in Africa, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Rural Politics in Tanzania, 1961-1968, undated (Box 4)
    - Sierra Leone,, undated, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - Sierra Leone and Liberia- Comparisons and Contrasts, undated (Box 4)
    - Significance of Ordinance undated, 1984 (Box 4)
    - South Africa,, undated, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
    - South Africa – Prospectus for Change,, undated, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Southern Province- Tanzania, undated, 1956 (Box 4)
    - Soviet Foreign Policy, undated, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Stress and Strains, undated (Box 4)
    - Sukumaland, undated (Box 4)
    - Supervision of Agriculture Officers, undated (Box 4)
    - Suspension and Removal of Chiefs, undated (Box 4)
    - Tanzania,, undated, 1949-1968 (Box 4)
    - Tanzania,, undated, 1976-1980 (Box 4)
    - Tax Collection, undated (Box 4)
    - Traditional Period, undated (Box 4)
    - Treatment of Indians, undated (Box 4)
    - Tribal Composition, undated (Box 4)
    - Tribal Ethnology undated, 1949-1966 (Box 4)
    - Tribal Notesundated, 1959-1960 (Box 4)
    - Turu, undated (Box 4)
    - Unification Policy Evaluationundated, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - Water and Health, undated, 1968-1982 (Box 4)
  - Other Indiana University Materials (Box 5)
    - American Association of University Professors (Box 5)
      - Addresses And Membership Lists, 1976-1981 (Box 5)
      - "AAUP Bulletin", 1977-1978 (Box 5)
      - "AAUP News", 1978-1981 (Box 5)
      - Collective Bargaining, undated, 1977-1981 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, undated, 1977-1980 (Box 5)
      - Executive Committee, undated, 1974-1981 (Box 5)
      - Houston Annual Meeting, undated, 1979 (Box 5)
      - "Indiana Academe", 1977-1981 (Box 5)
      - Indiana Conference, undated, 1979 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous, undated, 1971-1980 (Box 5)
      - Speech, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Academic Affairs – Background, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Administration - News Clippings, 1966-1978 (Box 5)
    - Alumni African Safari, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Area Studies Review, 1973 (Box 5)
    - College of Arts and Science,, undated, 1977-1989 (Box 5)
    - Committee Procedures Re: Confidential Records, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Concerned Titled Professors, 1978-1992, undated (Box 5)
    - Correspondence – IU Offer, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
    - Course Development, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    - Dissertation Study, undated, 1972-1975 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Documents, 1979-1984 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Ranks Documents, 1973-1977 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Report, 1958-1970; 1979-1980; 1980-1981; 1981-1982; 1983-1984; 1984; 1985; 1986; 1987; 1988; 1988-1989 (Box 5)
      1958-1970, undated
      1979-1980
      1980-1981
      1981-1982
      1983-1984
      1984
      1985
      1986
      1987
      1988
      1988-1989
    - Financial Retrenchment, 1980 (Box 5)
    - "Focus: Black America" Notes, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Foreign Area Fellowship Program, undated, 1959-1967 (Box 5)
    - Fulbright Committee, undated, 1988-1990 (Box 5)
    - Grad Council, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - Grad Council, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - Grad Council,, undated, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - Grad Council, Inter-Campus Affairs Committee, undated, 1975-1978 (Box 6)
    - Grad Council Meeting Minutes, 1975-1980 (Box 6)
    - Herman B Wells Remarks at Jean Sutton's Memorial, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Indiana Alumni Magazine, March, 1971 (Box 6)
    - IU Foundation, 1969-1980 (Box 6)
    - IU Foundation – News Clippings,, undated, 1979-1986 (Box 6)
    - Inter-Campus Affairs Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - J. Gus Liebenow Personnel Data, 1953-1968 (Box 6)
    - Leo R. Dowling Memorial Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - Operation Classroom, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Organization of Academic Affairs, 1972-1974, undated (Box 6)
    - Personnel Committee, undated, 1984-1988 (Box 6)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, undated, 1975-1989 (Box 6)
    - Regional Campus Administration, undated, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Resignation as Vice President and Dean for Academic Affairs, 1974 (Box 6)
    - "The Review", 1976 (Box 6)
    - Sabbatical, 1977-1984 (Box 6)
    - Search Committee – Research and Graduate Development Dean, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - Semester at Sea, undated, 1980-1988 (Box 6)
    - Social Service Expansion, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Speech Material (Box 6)
      - Accountability of University, 1973 (Box 6)
      - "Current University Problems", 1974 (Box 6)
      - Minority Affairs Conference, 1974 (Box 6)
      - Other, undated, 1973 (Box 6)
      - Phi Beta Kappa, 1976 (Box 6)
      - Presidential Remarks, undated, 1973 (Box 6)
      - Tenure Quotas, 1973 (Box 6)
    - State of the Campus Address, 1979 (Box 6)
    - "Structures of Universities", undated (Box 6)
    - Student Fee Study, 1976-1979 (Box 6)
    - University Division,, undated, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
    - The University System, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - "What Professors Do", undated, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - X125 Residential Learning, undated, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Political Science
    - American Political Science Review, 1963-1975 (Box 6)
    - Atlantic Richfield Company,, undated, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - Center for Latin America, undated, 1976 (Box 6)
    - China,, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 6)
    - Comparative Politics Working Group, undated, 1977-1982 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1975-1989 (Box 6)
    - Courses and Schedules, undated, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Defense Institute of Security Assistant Management, undated, 1983-1987 (Box 6)
    - Enrollment Information, undated, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Finances, 1983-1988 (Box 6)
    - GM Purchasing International Seminar, undated, 1976-1979 (Box 7)
    - Grade Books, 1958-1968 (Box 7)
    - Graduate Counseling, 1976-1984 (Box 7)
    - Guide to Graduate Study, 1978-1980 (Box 7)
    - Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1977-1988 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1978-1991 (Box 7)
    - Personal Correspondence, undated, 1988-1990 (Box 7)
    - Ph.D. Exam Questions, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Policies, undated, 1983-1986 (Box 7)
    - Political Science Award and Publication Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
    - Promotion/Tenure, 1977-1983 (Box 7)
    - Promotion/Tenure, undated, 1984-1987 (Box 7)
    - Public Discussion Opportunities Series, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Recruitment Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
    - Regional Integration in Africa, undated (Box 7)
    - Research Collection Committee, 1982-1984 (Box 7)
    - Rudy Professor of Political Science, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
    - St. Mary's Symposium, undated, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Selected Acquisitions, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Sierra Leone Studies Symposium,, undated, 1981 (Box 7)
    - South Africa, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - U.S. China Conference on Africa, undated, 1986-1988 (Box 7)
    - U.S. Constitution, undated, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Universities Society for Propogation of the Gospel, undated, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Weekly Bulletins, 1979-1988 (Box 7)
- Outside Organizations
  - African Advisory Council, undated, 1970-1972 (Box 7)
  - African-American Institute,, undated, 1975-1994 (Box 7)
  - African-Caribbean Institute,, undated, 1985-1989 (Box 7)
  - African Research Committee, 1966 (Box 7)
  - African Studies Association (Box 8)
    - 18th Annual Meeting, 1975 (Box 8)
    - 19th Annual Meeting, 1976 (Box 8)
    - 21st Annual Meeting, 1978 (Box 8)
    - 22nd Annual Meeting, undated, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - 24th Annual Meeting, 1977-1981 (Box 8)
    - 30th Annual Meeting, undated, 1987 (Box 8)
    - "ASA News", 1991 (Box 8)
    - Administrative Information, undated (Box 8)
    - Annual Meeting Handbook, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Annual Meeting Problems and Procedures, undated, 1976-1979 (Box 8)
    - Archives-Libraries Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Association of Concerned African Scholars, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Auditor's Report, 1970-1979 (Box 8)
    - Blank Forms, undated (Box 8)
    - British Consulate General, 1914 (Box 8)
    - By-Laws, undated, 1970-1980 (Box 8)
    - Constituency Committee, undated, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1979-1988 (Box 8)
    - Creation of ASA, 1957 (Box 8)
    - Development Committee, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, undated, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Executive Secretary, 1978/1979 (Box 8)
    - Finances, 1971-1980 (Box 8)
    - "Liberia Watch", 1990 (Box 8)
    - MacArthur Scholar Awards, undated, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Mailing List, undated (Box 8)
    - Minutes, 1969-1979 (Box 8)
    - Nominations, undated, 1975-1980 (Box 8)
    - Notes, etc., undated, 1978-1980 (Box 8)
    - Past Officers, undated (Box 8)
    - Photographs, 1981-1990 (Box 8)
    - Political Resolutions, undated, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
    - Presidential Speech, undated, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Publications Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
    - Questionnaires, undated (Box 8)
    - Registration Fee Reimbursement, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Reports, undated, 1968-1976 (Box 8)
    - Robinson Award Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
    - Romero/Hoskins Controversy, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - South Africa, undated (Box 8)
    - Travel Reimbursement, undated, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Wingspread Conference, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Asean Institute,, undated, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Bloomington Area Arts Council,, undated, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace,, undated, 1984-1986 (Box 8)
  - Catholic Relief Services, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Center for Advanced Study of International Development, Undated, 1981-1984 (Box 8)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies,, undated, 1982-1984 (Box 8)
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare, undated, 1971-1977 (Box 8)
  - Department of State,, undated, 1980-1994 (Box 8)
  - East African Institute, undated, 1956-1959 (Box 8)
  - Eisenhower Foundation,, undated, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Ford Foundation,, undated, 1962-1968 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Service Insititute,, undated, 1966-1984 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Relations Committee's Subcommittee on Africa - Liebenow Testimony,, undated, 1981-1994 (Box 9)
  - Foreign Service Institute,, undated, 1966-1984 (Box 9)
  - Friends of Liberia
    - Correspondence, 1987-1997 (Box 9)
    - Funding Proposal, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
    - Liberian News from World Press, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1993-1998 (Box 9)
    - Newsletters, 1988-1998 (Box 9)
  - George C. Marshall Foundation,, undated, 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Indiana Consortium for International Programs, 1980-1982 (Box 9)
  - Institute for Development Anthropology, Inc. (consulting project), undated, 1983- 1985 (Box 9)
  - Institute for Foreign Policy-Africa Project, undated, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Intermediate Technology Development Group,, undated, 1981-1985 (Box 9)
  - International African Institute
    - Administrative Information, 1949-1982 (Box 9)
    - Bulletins, 1976-1979 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1964-1983 (Box 9)
    - Executive Council, 1978-1983 (Box 9)
    - Finances, undated, 1977-1983 (Box 9)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1977-1982 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1976-1983 (Box 9)
    - Publications, undated, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Reports, undated, 1965-1982 (Box 9)
    - "Ventures" Broadcast, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
  - International Communication Agency, undated, 1979-1982 (Box 9)
  - International Research and Exhanges Board, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Latin American Studies Association, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Liberia Working Group,, undated, 1984-1993 (Box 9)
  - Liberian Community Associationundated, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Liberian Studies Association
    - 11th Annual Conference, 1979 (Box 9)
    - 13th Annual Conference, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - 14th Annual Conference, 1982 (Box 9)
    - 15th Annual Conference, 1983 (Box 9)
    - 16th Annual Conference, 1984 (Box 9)
    - 17th Annual Conference, 1985 (Box 9)
    - 19th Annual Conference, 1987 (Box 9)
    - 20th Annual Conference, undated, 1988 (Box 9)
    - 21st Annual Conference, 1989 (Box 9)
    - 22nd Annual Conference, 1990 (Box 9)
    - 23rd Annual Conference, undated, 1991 (Box 9)
    - 39th Annual Conference, 2007 (Box 9)
    - Addresses, undated, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    - Addresses, undated, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Incorporation, undated, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
    - Liberian Studies Conference Papers, undated, 1969-1979 (Box 9)
    - "Liberian Studies Journal", 1983-1986 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1981-1989 (Box 9)
    - Publications, undated, 1983 (Box 9)